在早期的一次演讲中，我们讨论了数据不匹配问题。这就是事实
In a much earlier lecture, we talked about the data mismatch problem. That's the fact
像相机这样的传感器发出大量像素，可能是100万像素
that a sensor like a camera emits a large number of pixels, perhaps 1 million pixels
在每个图像中，它将输出每秒10到50个图像的任何内容
in every image and it's going to be outputting anything from 10 to 50 images per second that is an
大量的数据。
enormous amount of data.
像机器人这样的机器需要相对较少的信息才能告诉它在哪里
A machine like a robot requires relatively little information in order to tell it where
去这里所示的臂式机械手只需要6个数字来描述
to go an arm type manipulator like shown here requires simply 6 numbers which described
机器人关节的角度。
the angles of the joints of the robot.
像真空吸尘器这样的移动机器人在这里显示实际上只需要2个数字来控制
A mobile robot like the vacuum cleaner shows here really only requires 2 numbers to control
它的运动，即它的前进速度V和它的旋转速度omega。
its motion, that's its forward velocity V and its rotational velocity omega.
因此，相对而言，我们遇到来自相机传感器的大量数据的问题
So, we have the problem with a huge amount of data coming from a camera sensor, relatively
机器人所需的数据很少。我们解决这个问题的方法是提取什么
little data required by the robot. The way we get around that then is to extract what
我们从图像中调用特征，我们在之前的关于区域的讲座中谈了一些
we call features from the image and we've talked a bit in previous lectures about region
特征。我们已经讨论过如何获取导入图像。我们可以找到哪些地区
features. We've talked about how we can take an import image. We can find regions which
是具有相似强度或相似颜色的像素组，然后我们可以描述
are sets of pixels with either similar intensity or with similar color and we can then describe
那些区域的质心，边界框，时刻周长，
those regions in terms of their centroid, their bounding box, moment’s perimeter,
圆形等。
circularity and so on.
我们已经谈了很多关于地区的事情，但是还有很多其他类型的功能
We've talked a lot about regions but there are number of other types of features that
非常有用和有趣，我想谈谈一下。
are really useful and interesting and that I'd like to talk a little bit about.
大多数真实场景包含很多行。这是一个教堂的特殊图片，我
Most real world scenes contain a lot of lines. This particular picture of a church, I've
突出了很多行。其中一些线条来自屋顶之间的对比
highlighted a number of lines. Some of these lines come from the contrast between the roof
和天空，在屋顶和墙壁之间，窗户的边缘，门的边缘和
and the sky, between the roof and the wall, the edges of windows, the edges of doors and
等等。当然，在任何人造环境中，都有大量的线条，甚至是
so on. Certainly, in any man-made environment, there are enormous number of lines but even
在许多自然环境中也有线条，也许是树木的垂直边缘
in many natural environments there are lines as well, perhaps the vertical edges of tree
树干等等。
trunks and so on.
因此，线条在环境中非常普遍，线条非常简单和紧凑。
So, lines are very prevalent in the environment and lines are very simple and compact to describe.
一条线可能包含大量像素，但实际上仅用2个参数描述，
A line might contain a large number of pixels but is really described by just 2 parameters,
它的拦截和它的斜率。
its intercept and its slope.
现在，一个有趣的问题是：我们如何在图像中提取线条，重要的是，
Now, an interesting question then is: How do we extract lines in an image, the important,
图像中的主导线？
the dominant lines within an image?
我们称之为点特征的另一类特征以及覆盖在这张图上的内容
Another class of features what we call point features and what's overlaid on this picture
这里的建筑物是图像中有趣的点，也就是他们所描述的
of a building here are points in the image that are interesting, that is they describe
这些点非常有特色，如果我拍下这栋建筑的另一张照片，我会
points that are quite distinctive and if I took another picture of this building, I'd
很有可能在同一建筑物的不同视图中找到相同的点。
have a pretty good chance of finding those same points in a different view of the same building.
所以，如果我移动相机，如果太阳出来，太阳就会落在云层后面，我愿意
So, if I'd move my camera, if the sun's come out, the sun's going behind the cloud, I would
仍然能够找到这些点。重叠的图形信息需要很多
still be able to locate these points. The overlaid graphical information entails a lot
关于这些特征点。圆圈的中心表示这个独特的中心
about these feature points. The centre of the circle indicates the centre of this distinctive
模式，这是我们很可能在另一个视图中找到的模式
pattern that is a pattern that we are very likely to be able to find in another view
相同的场景。
of the same scene.
圆的大小表示模式的比例。这是非常的
The size of the circle indicates something about the scale of the pattern. Is it a very
小的独特图案或大的独特图案？无线电线说了些什么
small distinct pattern or a large distinct pattern? The radio lines say something about
该模式的方向。
the orientation of that pattern.